Why is this ice in Antarctica so blue?
Look at it. Normally, ice is full of air
bubbles, which make the light scatter so
it looks white. But in a glacier, the
ice and snow build up over hundreds or
millions of years, smooshing it
together. And that pressure forces out
the air bubbles, leaving much larger,
denser ice crystals that absorb red and
yellow light and reflect back this
bright blue color. But you don't have to
be deep underground to see this. This
map shows where the blue ice is on the
surface. And look at this huge
concentration by this mountain range.
Here, [music] ice sheets flow directly
into the mountains and they get pushed
up. So, strong winds vaporize the top
layers of snow, revealing these stunning
layers underneath. And maybe the
craziest thing is [music] this ice is so
dense you can land a plane on it. We did
that. You want to see it? Subscribe.